very good and welcome once again to
beta tech if this is the first video
you've made on the channel we talk
about software and technology so
if you're interested in development you've come to the
right place after uploading some
videos on object oriented programming I've
realized that you guys really like this whole
systems design thing both
internal software and
architecture so
I'm happy to say that this is going to be the
first video in a series of videos
on design patterns the idea is
simple try to make a video for
each pattern put them all together in a
playlist and be able to say that we've
compiled all the design patterns in video
but before we get into a
series that I warn you won't be short I
think it's better to first explain what
design patterns are why they
exist and see a little bit how they are classified
more than anything I don't think it's going to be much use to
explain each one of these
concepts without first having an
introduction so let's get to work
and explain once and for all what the
heck this design patterns thing is
we can say that a design pattern is
a recipe an action plan a
description of a  problem along with a
way to solve it in other
professions such as in
architecture
many patterns reusable elements are used
to solve
recurring problems that are found in
everyday life when they are said in buildings
for example examples of these patterns
could be arches to support
large loads or bridges to
overcome obstacles in this way
architects can design
more complex solutions by combining these elements
with each other developers
also have similar tools
throughout history there have been
problems in software development
that have appeared again and again and
that coincidentally were solved in a
similar way these problems were
general enough to be
able to appear in different situations
with different languages and with
different architectures and in fact
most solutions
also stop in a general way
therefore they are recipes that will serve you in
many different environments for example
both in front-end and MBA in
summary a design pattern defines a
solution to a recurring problem and this
solution can be replicated and implemented
in various ways depending on the
technology
or language to define these
patterns normally
graphics are used as patterns are usually
class constructions and
definition of  relationships between
them these graphics are normally
u ml diagrams or similar in this series
of videos I will try to explain with
examples and in the most understandable way
possible these class relationships
explaining the problems that are
solved each pattern and in some
cases the consequences or complications
that can emerge from using them
so as I said this video is going to
be the introduction point and
therefore I think it is necessary to teach you the
classification of the different
design patterns in a basic way how they are
grouped together and normally
the patterns are classified into three
general fields the creational patterns
are the structural patterns and the
behavioral patterns the
national patterns are those that are
responsible for solving problems that
involve the creation of objects
their objective is to provide solutions to be able to
create specific instances of certain
objects for example if we have a
complex class hierarchy useful
type of patterns can help us
keep our code free of
infinite ipsi infinite switches or the
set to better understand the
problem imagine that you are
developing a video game you have
several types of enemies it is a video game
where the enemies appear on the map
randomly and therefore you
want both the type of enemy
and their position to  decide at
runtime all enemies inherit from
the enemy class so to decide
which specific enemy we want to use
you have logic in several parts of your code
to know which class to use this
can end up being a problem because it
will not be easy to add a
new enemy you will have to touch many parts
of the code to make it work and the
same will happen if at any time
you want to eliminate some type of enemy that is
where the
alex creation patterns would come in and in this specific case the
pattern is called factor and they also
help us in case we have for
example a very complex object to
build the creation of this object
can be very complicated and they give us
patterns that can help us both
simplify this creation and make it
more understandable continuing with the example
of the video game you may
think that creating the level map can
be very difficult the map class has
many parameters and therefore
building it is not simple another problem
that we can solve in this case
using the wilder pattern the next
family of patterns that we are going to see is that
of structural patterns these
patterns help us when
configuring relationships between objects
still continuing with the example of the
video game we have seen that we have
a set of enemies the enemy class
in turn is a  game entity in the
same way as npcs and power
apps we define a game entity
as something that has a certain logic and that is
updated in each iteration of the
game club therefore we have that each
time the game loop is executed each time
the iteration makes a pass we
consider all the entities in the game
and call the function to update their
logic in this way all the entities
move depending on their state
the enemies look for you the npcs
wait for you and the power apps appear or
disappear but now let's put the case
in which there is an enemy that what it does is
create more enemies it is an enemy that
generates some small minions around it
so
that they go to attack these minions
are obviously also entities and
therefore they have to be updated each
time the game loop is executed
but we want the big enemy to
die all his millions to also
die therefore these minions
depend in some way on the
life cycle of their creator so it is no use to us
that in some magical way they are added
to the list of global entities of the
game this is a problem that we can
solve using the pattern
composite that gives us a special way
to organize our entities
assuming that each entity can have
entities within it recursively
and finally we have the
behavior patterns that help us perform
interaction between classes or objects
so that we can distribute the
responsibilities of each of these
elements in a much more
organized way in our video game each
enemy attacks in a different way
some run towards you to
hit you and others throw projectiles
from afar a simple way to
implement this would be to define within
the logic of each enemy these
attack patterns so that all
enemies of the same type always attack the
same but let's imagine that we want
a little more game we want to add a
new more fearsome enemy that has
much more life that is bigger but
although it costs much more to kill
following the same attack pattern as the
first one we had seen simply
runs towards you to hit you we could
duplicate all the code and put it in the
new enemy but as you know
developers do not like to repeat
work this is a perfect case in
which using the strategy pattern would
give us a very useful solution that would
allow us to decouple the
behaviors the types of attacks of
the enemies giving us the option  to be
much more variable in our video from
here on there is no other option but to
start explaining the
design patterns the idea is that this video is the
limit of the series therefore I will be
leaving in the description all the
videos about design patterns
classifying them obviously by their
family if you like this initiative
please subscribe to my channel and leave me
a good light and do not forget to leave me a
comment saying what design pattern
you want to see first I hope this
series helps you and if much more we will see each other
in the next video goodbye